<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EPC Alpha</title>
    <link>https://notbinary.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on EPC Alpha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://notbinary.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 02</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/week-notes/week-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/week-notes/week-02/</guid>
      <description>This tool will assist publishers ensure their publication meets a standard, such as the brownfield sites register standard, and the emerging standards for Local Plans and Section 106.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype 01</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/prototype/prototype-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/prototype/prototype-01/</guid>
      <description>https://mhclg-epc-alpha-prototype-01.herokuapp.com/
This tool will assist publishers ensure their publication meets a standard, such as the brownfield sites register standard, and the emerging standards for Local Plans and Section 106.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/week-notes/week-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/week-notes/week-01/</guid>
      <description>This tool will assist publishers ensure their publication meets a standard, such as the brownfield sites register standard, and the emerging standards for Local Plans and Section 106.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to data in bulk</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/access-to-data-in-bulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/access-to-data-in-bulk/</guid>
      <description>When building a service, I want to be able to access data in bulk, so that I do not have to make multiple requests for data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to raw data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/maintained-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/maintained-data/</guid>
      <description>When building a service, I want to have access to raw data (as opposed to calculated statistical data), so that I am able to get the fullest value from the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordable housing</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/affordable-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/affordable-housing/</guid>
      <description>Affordable housing includes social rented, affordable rented and intermediate housing, provided to specified eligible households whose needs are not met by the market. It can be a new-build property or a private sector property that has been purchased for use as an affordable home.
Each year Homes England publish statistics on the supply of affordable homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality management</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/air-quality-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/air-quality-management/</guid>
      <description>In an effort to reduce air pollution the Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs have set air quality targets for each local authority.
When a local authority identifies an area where they are at risk of not meeting their target they must set an Air Quality Action Plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aircraft noise</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/aircraft-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/aircraft-noise/</guid>
      <description>Land located close to airports and flight paths may be subject to aircraft noise. This noise is classified in three ways:
 Mechanical noise — rotation of the engine parts, most noticeable when fan blades reach supersonic speeds Aerodynamic noise — from the airflow around the surfaces of the aircraft, especially when flying low at high speeds Noise from aircraft systems — cockpit and cabin pressurization and conditioning systems, and Auxiliary Power units  The Aviation Policy Framework outlines planning considerations with regards to aircraft noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Monuments and Archaeological Areas Act 1979</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1979-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1979-46/</guid>
      <description>Regulations relating to the the preservation of ancient monuments and sites of archaeological or historic importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Monuments and Archaeological Sites</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ancient-monuments-and-archaeological-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ancient-monuments-and-archaeological-sites/</guid>
      <description>Sites of archaeological or historic importance are protected by the Ancient Monuments and Archaeological Areas Act 1979 and are listed on the National Heritage List for England. This gives them legally protected status.
In order to carry out any work to a scheduled ancient monument or site you will need to apply to Historic England for a Scheduled Monument Consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual monitoring report</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/annual-monitoring-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/annual-monitoring-report/</guid>
      <description>The annual monitoting report is forms a part of the Local Plan.
It&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to assess:
 Are policies achieving their objectives, and is sustainable development being delivered? Have policies had the intended consequences? Are the assumptions and objectives behind policies still relevant? Are the targets set in the Local Development Framework being achieved?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Area of archaeological potential</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/area-of-archaeological-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/area-of-archaeological-potential/</guid>
      <description>These are area&amp;rsquo;s where there is a possibility of buried archeology. If a planning application is submitted on one of these sites the case will referred to a county archaeologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark land value</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/benchmark-land-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/benchmark-land-value/</guid>
      <description>Benchmark land value is the estimated cost of the land given its current use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/brownfield-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/brownfield-site/</guid>
      <description>Are often on disused or derelict land. Are more available in the North and Midlands (but most housing demand is in the south east). Are valuable as existing buildings can be split up into more homes on any one site. The site has already been developed so reduces urban sprawl. Use unsightly areas for building developments, so improves the urban environment. Are found in urban areas, so building housing there reduces demand on car use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</guid>
      <description>All local authorities must publish a register of brownfield sites.
We were interested in learning about how this policy was implemented, the process that local authorities follow to publish the data, and whether there were any tools that we could build to help people collect and maintain the data.
Prototypes In progress A way of validating the collected data   Our hypothesis Through speaking with local authorities we understood that often times the person responsible for collecting the brownfield site data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building age</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/building-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/building-age/</guid>
      <description>The Valuation Office Agency frequently publish data on the year (or year range) of when a building was built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building use</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/building-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/building-use/</guid>
      <description>Planning use cases determine what an individual property may be used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community infrastructure levy</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/community-infrastructure-levy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/community-infrastructure-levy/</guid>
      <description>The Community Infrastructure Levy (CIL) is a planning charge, introduced by the Planning Act 2008 as a tool for local authorities in England and Wales to help deliver infrastructure to support the development of their area. It came into force on 6 April 2010 through the Community Infrastructure Levy Regulations 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complusory Purchase Orders</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/complusory-purchase-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/complusory-purchase-orders/</guid>
      <description> Current areas of investigation Upcoming areas of investigation We plan to explore the following by prototyping tools and by testing and consulting with people involved with developer contributions, and responding to your feedback.
We will regularly add updates to the following issues on github:
 Timeline </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Con29</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/con29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/con29/</guid>
      <description>The CON29 form has been in use for over 50 years and was created to complement the Local Land Charges Register search. The form contains a standard set of enquiries agreed by central government, the Law Society and local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation area</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/conservation-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/conservation-area/</guid>
      <description>As defined in the [Planning (Listed Buildings and Conservation Areas) Act 1990(https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1990/9/contents) a conservation area is an area considered worthy of preservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contaminated Land</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/contaminated-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/contaminated-land/</guid>
      <description>Land is legally defined as ‘contaminated land’ where substances are causing or could cause:
 significant harm to people, property or protected species significant pollution of surface waters (for example lakes and rivers) or groundwater harm to people as a result of radioactivity  Contaminated land may previously have been used as a:
 factory mine steel mill refinery landfill  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Tax</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/council-tax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/council-tax/</guid>
      <description>Introduced in the Local Government Finance Act 1992, Council Tax is a tax on domestic property.
There are eight council tax bands (A to H) for which a property will fall into one of based on the property value as determined by the Valuation Office Agency.
The amount of council tax owed for each band is determined by each local authority and various discount or reduction schemes apply, such as a discount for sole occupancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Park</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/country-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/country-park/</guid>
      <description>A country park is an area designated for people to visit and enjoy recreation in a countryside environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countryside and Rights of Way Act 2000</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2000-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2000-37/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crown Copyright</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/crown-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/crown-copyright/</guid>
      <description>© Crown copyright and database right 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crown Copyright and Ordnance Survey</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/crown-copyright-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/crown-copyright-os/</guid>
      <description>© Crown copyright and database rights 2018 Ordnance Survey 100026316.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Maintainer</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/users/data-maintainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/users/data-maintainer/</guid>
      <description>Developers complying with regulations, local authorities collecting land and housing data, and others submitting or updating data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Modeller</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/users/data-modeller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/users/data-modeller/</guid>
      <description>People who create data specifications, such as those commissioned by councils to write the specifications for land and housing datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Developer contributions is the collective term for Section 106 and CIL, which are levied on developers by local authorities to pay for the local infrastructure necessary for new developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Help us develop a common data format This page documents the alpha phase for developing a format for representing developer contributions as data.
You can help us improve the format by:
 participating in the discussion on our GitHub issues making comments using our feedback form  We will continue to develop the format as we learn from testing the format with data and the prototypes with users.
We would particularly like to hear from local planning authorities who are able to make their developer contributions public and would be willing to participate in our user research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Corporation</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/development-corporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/development-corporation/</guid>
      <description>Development Corporations are organisations, established byt the Government, for the purpose of urban development. They are often for the development of new surbudan areas or the redevelopment of existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy access to data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/easy-access-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/easy-access-to-data/</guid>
      <description>When building a service, I want access to data without having to ask for it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Performance Certificate Data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/energy-performance-certificate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/energy-performance-certificate-data/</guid>
      <description>Energy Performance Certificates (EPCs) are needed whenever a property is:
 built sold rented  You must order an EPC for potential buyers and tenants before you market your property to sell or rent.
An EPC contains:
 information about a property’s energy use and typical energy costs recommendations about how to reduce energy use and save money  An EPC gives a property an energy efficiency rating from A (most efficient) to G (least efficient) and is valid for 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensure data meets the specification</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/ensure-data-meets-the-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/ensure-data-meets-the-specification/</guid>
      <description>Before publishing a data, I want to be able to validate that data I&amp;rsquo;ve collect meets the specification, so that I can fix any issues</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment Agency Conditional Licence</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/environment-agency-conditional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/environment-agency-conditional/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood zone</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/flood-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/flood-zone/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden thread of building information</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</guid>
      <description>In the 2018 Independent Review of Building Regulations and Fire Safety there is a recommendation that there is a &amp;lsquo;digital record&amp;rsquo; for buildings. We are working with the Building Safety Programme to understand what a &amp;lsquo;digital record&amp;rsquo; might look like, and how the data could be collected and made available.
Prototypes We&amp;rsquo;ve not yet started to prototype for this project.
Next steps  we&amp;rsquo;re meeting with the team from the Building Safety Programme to demo the work we&amp;rsquo;ve done so far around Developer Contributions and Brownfield Sites  Data fields The specification has not yet defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenbelt</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/greenbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/greenbelt/</guid>
      <description>A policy for controlling urban growth and sprawl. Rings of countryside where urbanisation will be resisted for the foreseeable future, maintaining an area where agriculture, forestry and outdoor leisure can prevail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenfield site</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/greenfield-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/greenfield-site/</guid>
      <description>Greenfield land is undeveloped land in either a city or urban area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gross development value</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/gross-development-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/gross-development-value/</guid>
      <description>Gross development value is the estimated value that a new development could fetch. To work out the gross development value the property developer needs to factor in the percentage of affordable housing that the relevant local authority states in their local plan policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and safety executive</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/health-and-safety-executive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/health-and-safety-executive/</guid>
      <description>The Health and Safety Executive is the body responsible for the encouragement, regulation and enforcement of workplace health, safety and welfare, and for research into occupational risks in Great Britain. It is a non-departmental public body of the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic England Copyright</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/historic-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/historic-england/</guid>
      <description>© Historic England 2018. Contains Ordnance Survey data © Crown copyright and database right 2018 The Historic England GIS Data contained in this material was obtained on 21 April 2018. The most publicly available up to date Historic England GIS Data can be obtained from http://www.HistoricEngland.org.uk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic England GIS terms</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/historic-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/historic-england/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic map vectors</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/historic-map-vectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/historic-map-vectors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing benefit</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/housing-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/housing-benefit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing waiting list</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/housing-waiting-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/housing-waiting-list/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INSPIRE End User Licence</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/inspire-end-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/inspire-end-user/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Registry INSPIRE</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/land-registry-inspire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/land-registry-inspire/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Terrier</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/land-terrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/land-terrier/</guid>
      <description>A land terrier is a record system for an institution&amp;rsquo;s land and property holdings. It differs from a land registry in that it is maintained for the organisation&amp;rsquo;s own needs and may not be publicly accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listed Building</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/listed-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/listed-building/</guid>
      <description>Status attributed to buildings with special architectural or historical interest. Results in additional restrictions being applied in the planning system in an attempt to protect it for future generations. There are categories of listed buildings, called Grades. The higher the grade the more restrictions that apply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Land Charges Act 1975</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpa-1975-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpa-1975-76/</guid>
      <description>An Act to make fresh provision for and in connection with the keeping of local land charges registers and the registration of matters therein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Plans</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/local-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/local-plans/</guid>
      <description>Local plans set out local planning policies and identify how land is used, determining what will be built where. They are a rich source of information, but the equally useful data used to produce them isn’t easily extracted from them.
The Ministry of Housing, Communities and Local Government is working with local planning authorities to design a data format for publishing local plan data so that it’s easy to find, use and trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local development scheme</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-development-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-development-scheme/</guid>
      <description>Local development schemes are public &amp;lsquo;project plans&amp;rsquo; which identify which local development documents will be produced, in what order and when. It became a statutory requirement for local planning authorities in the UK to produce these schemes under the Planning and Compulsory Purchase Act 2004.
The local development scheme acts as the starting point for the community and stakeholders to find out about the local authority&amp;rsquo;s planning policies in respect to a particular place or issue, and what the status of those policies is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local land charge</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-land-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-land-charge/</guid>
      <description>A local land charge is a restriction on a piece of land or property that can limit its use or bind the owner to a payment of a sum of money. Charges can include:
 planning decisions road agreements tree preservation orders conservation areas and listed buildings notices environmental health notices charges or objections made against previous owners  A local land charges search will highlight these charges and help you to make an informed choice about buying the parcel of land or property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local plan</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-plan/</guid>
      <description>A local plan sets out local planning policies and identifies how land is used, determining what will be built where. Adopted local plans provide the framework for development across England. Local peoples&amp;rsquo; views are vital in shaping a local plan, helping determine how their community develops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local planning authority</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-planning-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/local-planning-authority/</guid>
      <description>A local planning authority is the local government body that is empowered by law to exercise urban planning functions for a particular area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localism Act 2011</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2011-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2011-20/</guid>
      <description>An Act to make provision about the functions and procedures of local and certain other authorities; to make provision about the functions of the Commission for Local Administration in England; to enable the recovery of financial sanctions imposed by the Court of Justice of the European Union on the United Kingdom from local and public authorities; to make provision about local government finance; to make provision about town and country planning, the Community Infrastructure Levy and the authorisation of nationally significant infrastructure projects; to make provision about social and other housing; to make provision about regeneration in London; and for connected purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintained data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/access-to-raw-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/access-to-raw-data/</guid>
      <description>When using a dataset, I want to have confidence that the dataset is being maintained, so that I can trust that the data is relevent and usable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mineral safeguarding area</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/mineral-safeguarding-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/mineral-safeguarding-area/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Park</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/national-park/</guid>
      <description>Areas in the UK designated under the National Parks and Access to the Countryside Act (2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Parks and Access to the Countryside Act 1949</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-geo6-12-13-14-97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-geo6-12-13-14-97/</guid>
      <description>An Act to make provision for National Parks and the establishment of a National Parks Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Planning Policy Framework</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/national-planning-policy-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/national-planning-policy-framework/</guid>
      <description>The revised National Planning Policy Framework (NPPF) was published on July 24th 2018 and sets out government&amp;rsquo;s planning policies for England and how these are expected to be applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural England Copyright</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/natural-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/natural-england/</guid>
      <description>© Natural England copyright. Contains Ordnance Survey data © Crown copyright and database right 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net development value</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/net-development-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/net-development-value/</guid>
      <description>The net development value is the estimated amount of money that a property development expects to make once all costs (land value, development, marketing etc) and sales have been taken into consideration.
As a part of the viability assessment a third party may work with a property developer and local authority to ensure that estimates reflect current market values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of stories</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/number-of-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/number-of-stories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of tenancy</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/number-of-tenancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/number-of-tenancy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONS Boundary</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/ons-boundary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/ons-boundary/</guid>
      <description>Contains National Statistics data © Crown copyright and database right 2018 Contains OS data © Crown copyright and database right 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Government Licence</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/ogl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/ogl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parking restriction</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/parking-restriction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/parking-restriction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Act 2008</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2008-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-2008-29/</guid>
      <description>The Planning Act 2008 introduced Community Infrastructure Levy planning charges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning and Compulsory Purchase Act 2004</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpha-2004-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpha-2004-5/</guid>
      <description>Regulation for local development schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Maker</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/users/policy-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/users/policy-maker/</guid>
      <description>Government policy professionals who decide what and how data must be supplied and maintained by developers, local authorities and others in the housing sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PropTech Developers</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/users/proptech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/users/proptech/</guid>
      <description>Software developers who create digital tools that use land and housing data to make it easier to develop, buy, sell or rent property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protected View</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/protected-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/protected-view/</guid>
      <description>A protected view or protected vista is the legal requirement within urban planning to preserve the view of a specific place or historic building from another location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide feedback</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/provide-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/provide-feedback/</guid>
      <description>When data is incorrect or missing, I want to be able to inform the data maintainer, so that they can fix the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish your developer contributions data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/guidance-and-standards/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/guidance-and-standards/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>The National Planning Policy Framework requires all local planning authorities and certain other organisations to publish their developer contributions data on a regular basis and in an agreed format. That format hasn’t yet been agreed, but the following guidance is a working approach that we plan to refine with your input.
Our aim is to develop a data format and publishing guidance that results in better insights into how developer contributions are supporting community infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radon</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/radon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/radon/</guid>
      <description>Radon is a colourless, odourless radioactive gas. It is formed by the radioactive decay of the small amounts of uranium that occur naturally in all rocks and soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramsar site</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ramsar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ramsar/</guid>
      <description>A Ramsar site is wetlands of international importance designated under the Ramsar Convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/safeguarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/safeguarding/</guid>
      <description>Safeguarding is an established part of the planning process, designed to ensure that land which has been identified for major infrastructure projects is protected from conflicting developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 106</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/section-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/section-106/</guid>
      <description>Section 106 is a legal agreement between an property developer and the local planning authority. It is used to mitigate the impact of any new property development to the local community and infrastructure.
The Section 106 agreement contains one or more developer contributions which support the generation of affordable housing, or contribute towards local infrastructure such as green spaces, schools or highway maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single register of planning</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</guid>
      <description>Overview here&amp;hellip;
Prototypes We&amp;rsquo;ve not yet started prototype for this project.
Next steps Data fields The specification has not yet defined.
Publications There are no publication for this specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site of special scientific interest</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/special-scientific-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/special-scientific-interest/</guid>
      <description>A Site of Special Scientific Interest (SSSI) is a formal conservation designation for an area which is of particular interest because of its fauna, flora or geological or physiological features.
Local authorities are required to have policies within their local plan to protect SSSIs, and should a planning application be submitted either on or close to the site then the appropriate conversation body must be consulted.
Orginally established in the National Parks and Access to the Countryside Act 1949.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenancy deposit</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tenancy-deposit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tenancy-deposit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenancy length</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tenancy-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tenancy-length/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Local Government Finance Act 1992</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1992-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1992-14/</guid>
      <description>Legislation introducing Council Tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Local Land Charges Rules 2018</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2018-273/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2018-273/</guid>
      <description>Regulations pertaining to the Local Land Charges Act 1975 including easements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Town and Country Planning (Local Planning) (England) Regulations 2012</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2012-605/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2012-605/</guid>
      <description>Legislation for Tree Preservation Orders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Town and Country Planning (Local Planning) (England) Regulations 2012</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2012-767/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/uksi-2012-767/</guid>
      <description>Regulations for local planning in England coming into force April 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Town and Country Planning Act 1990</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1990-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1990-8/</guid>
      <description>An Act to consolidate certain enactments relating to town and country planning (excluding special controls in respect of buildings and areas of special architectural or historic interest and in respect of hazardous substances) with amendments to give effect to recommendations of the Law Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree preservation order</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tree-preservation-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/tree-preservation-order/</guid>
      <description>A Tree Preservation Order is an order made by a local planning authority in England to protect specific trees, groups of trees or woodlands in the interests of amenity. An Order prohibit the:
 cutting down topping lopping uprooting wilful damage wilful destruction  of trees without the local planning authority’s written consent. If consent is given, it can be subject to conditions which have to be followed. In the Secretary of State’s view, cutting roots is also a prohibited activity and requires the authority’s consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknown Copyright</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/copyright/unknown/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknown Licence</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/licence/unknown/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unrestrictive usage</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/unrestrictive-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/unrestrictive-usage/</guid>
      <description>When building a service, I want to use data openly and without any prohibitive restrictions, so that I am able to get full value from the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up-to-date data</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/up-to-date-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/up-to-date-data/</guid>
      <description>When I am building a service, I want to have confidence that I have access to the most recent data, so that the thing I am building is useful and relevant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viability assessement</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/viability-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/viability-assessment/</guid>
      <description>A viability assessment is a part of the planning application process and is used to help a property development and local authority determine a fair developer contribution that will for a section 106 agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ward</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/ward/</guid>
      <description>Wards in the UK are electoral districts represented by one or more councillors. They are the primary unit of English electoral geography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waste sites</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/waste-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/glossary/waste-sites/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Resources Act 1991</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1991-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/legislation/ukpga-1991-57/</guid>
      <description>An Act of Parliment that that regulates water resources, water quality and pollution, and flood defence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What data is needed</title>
      <link>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/what-data-is-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notbinary.github.io/user-research/what-data-is-needed/</guid>
      <description>When defining a data standard, I want to know what data is needed, so that the right data is made available</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>